孩子
Hello.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
怎么了  亲爱的  是不是迷路了
What is it, dear? Are you lost?
新福尔摩斯 第2季 第2集
Sherlock S02E02 720p hdtv x264
巴斯克维尔的猎犬
- 无聊死了  - 你就这样搭地铁
- Well, that was tedious.  - You went on the tube like that?
出租车都不肯载我
None of the cabs would take me.
有新闻吗
Nothing?
乌干达军事政变
Military coup in Uganda.
又是一张你的照片  戴着那顶...
Another photo of you with the...
内阁重组
Well, um, Cabinet reshuffle?
就没点重要的事吗
Nothing of importance?
真要命
God!
约翰  我得来点  给我弄去
John, I need some. Get me some.
- 不行  - 给我弄点来
- No.  - Get me some.
不行  我们说好了完全戒烟
No. Cold turkey we agreed, no matter what.
反正你打点了附近所有商店  记得吗
Anyway, you've paid everyone off, remember?
两英里内没人会给你半根烟丝
No- one within a two- mile radius will sell you any.
这么蠢的主意是谁出的
Stupid idea. Whose idea was that?
赫德森太太
Mrs Hudson!
听着  夏洛克  你最近表现很好
Look, Sherlock, you're doing really well,
- 别前功尽弃  - 快告诉我放哪了
- don't give up now!  - Tell me where they are!
拜托  快说
Please, tell me.
求你
Please.
帮不了你  抱歉
Can't help, sorry.
我告诉你下周彩票中奖号码
I'll let you know next week's lottery numbers.
我就知道  可总得一试
It was worth a try.
我的私藏呢  把我的私房烟弄哪去了
My secret supply, what have you done with my secret supply?
香烟  你把它们藏哪了  藏哪了到底
Cigarettes, what have you done with them?  Where are they?
你根本不让我收拾你的东西
You never let me touch your things!
幸好你不让
Chance would be a fine thing.
- 记得你不是我们管家  - 的确不是
- I thought you weren't my housekeeper.  - I'm not.
来杯茶怎么样
How about a nice cuppa
也许你可以先把鱼叉放一边
and perhaps you could put away your harpoon?
茶不够劲儿
I need something stronger than tea.
得比茶高七成的威力才行
Seven percent stronger.
你又去找查特吉先生了吗
You've been to see Mr Chatterjee again.
什么
Pardon?
三明治店那个  你穿着新裙子
Sandwich shop. That's a new dress,
袖子上沾了面粉
but there's flour on the sleeve.
你不会穿成这样做点心
You wouldn't dress like that for baking.
- 夏洛克  - 指甲里有金属屑
- Sherlock...  - Thumbnail. Tiny traces of foil.
你又玩刮刮乐
Been at the scratch cards again.
我们都清楚你玩那东西没好结果
We all know where that leads, don't we?
皇城之夜
Kasbah Nights.
周一早上就擦这个有点太过了吧  你觉得呢
Pretty racy for a Monday morning, wouldn't you agree?
我写了篇关于香水鉴定的博客
I wrote a blog on the identification of perfumes.
就在我的网站上
It's on the website.
你该去看看
You should look it up!
- 够了吧  - 别指望那个查特吉
- Please!  - Don't pin your hopes on
会带你一起坐船出海了
that cruise with Mr Chatterjee,
他在唐卡斯特有老婆
he's got a wife in Doncaster
- 只是别人不知道   - 夏洛克
- that nobody knows about.  - Sherlock!
当然除了我
Well, nobody except me.
我不知道你在说什么  我真不知道
I don't know what you're talking about, I really don't!
你到底在搞什么飞机
What the bloody hell was all that about?
你不懂
You don't understand.
追上去  向她道歉
Go after her and apologise.
道歉
Apologise?
约翰  我真嫉妒你
John, I envy you so much.
你嫉妒我个什么
You envy me?
你的头脑  简单平和  基本不转
Your mind, it's so placid, straight- forward, barely used.
而我的就像个引擎  不受控制地转个没完
Mine's like an engine, racing out of control.
就像枚火箭  被卡在了发射台上
A rocket, tearing itself to pieces,
快被自己炸成碎片了
trapped on the launch pad.
我要新案子
I need a case!
你才刚解决了一个
You've just solved one,
而且还是用鱼叉叉头死猪
by harpooning a dead pig, apparently!
那都是早上的事了
That was this morning.
- 下一个呢  - 网站上没消息
- When's the next one?  - Nothing on the website?
亲爱的夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生
"Dear Mr Sherlock Holmes.
我的铃兰不见了
I can't find Bluebell anywhere.
求你了  能帮帮我吗
Please, please, please can you help?"
铃兰是啥鬼
Bluebell?
是只兔子  约翰  还有下文
A rabbit, John! But there's more.
铃兰失踪前  它开始发光
Before Bluebell disappeared, it turned luminous.
好像小精灵  这是小柯丝蒂的描述
"Like a fairy," According to little Kirsty.
第二天早上  铃兰就失踪了
Then the next morning, Bluebell was gone.
笼子锁着  没有强行闯入的痕迹
Hutch still locked, no sign of a forced entry.
我说啥来着  真是精彩
What am I saying, this is brilliant!
打给雷斯垂德
Phone Lestrade.
告诉他有只兔子跑了
Tell him there's an escaped rabbit.
你开玩笑
Are you serious?
不玩这个就玩妙探寻凶[推理卡牌]
It's this or Cluedo.
才不要  再也不跟你玩那个了
No. We are never playing that again.
- 为啥  - 因为凶手
- Why not?  - Because it's not actually possible
不能是被害人  夏洛克
for the victim to have done it, Sherlock. That's why.
这是唯一可能的解法
It was the only possible solution.
但这不符合游戏规则
It's not in the rules.
那就是游戏规则错了
Well, then, the rules are wrong!
一声铃
A single ring.
力度极大  还不到半秒
Maximum pressure, just under the half second.
是委托人
Client!
达特摩尔是个充满神话和传奇色彩的地方
Dartmoor, it's always been a place of myth and legend,
但在茫茫荒野中是否还隐藏着其他什么
but is there something else lurking out here?
某种真实存在的生物
Something very real.
达特摩尔一直以来也是
Dartmoor is also home to one
政府顶级机密行动的基地
the government's most secret of operations,
这里的生化武器研究中心
the chemical and biological weapons research centre,
敏感度据说甚至超过波顿镇实验室
which is said to be even more sensitive than Porton Down.
自二战结束后
Since the end of the Second World War,
关于巴斯克维尔实验的传闻
there have been persistent stories
从未断绝过
about the Baskerville experiments.
利用基因变异培养用于战场的生物
Genetic mutations, animals grown for the battlefield.
很多人相信在这些栅栏后
There are many who believe that within this compound,
在这片古老荒野的腹地中
in the heart of this ancient wildness,
有着超乎想象的恐怖存在
there are horrors beyond imagining.
但真正的问题是
But the real question is,
他们还被控制在基地内部吗
are all of them still inside?'
那时我还是个孩子
I was just a kid.
亨利・奈特
格林盆居民
就在那片荒原上
It was on the moor.
亨利的绘画（9岁）
天很黑  可我确定我看见了
It was dark, but I know what I saw.
我知道是什么东西杀死了我父亲
I know what killed my father.
你看见了什么
What did you see?
下面正要说到了
I was just about to say.
对  可那是电视采访
Yes, in a TV interview.
我更想听听原版
I prefer to do my own editing.
对  抱歉  当然了
Yes. Sorry, yes, of course.
不好意思
Excuse me.
不着急
In your own time.
还是快点
But quite quickly.
- 你知道达特摩尔吗  福尔摩斯先生  - 不
- Do you know Dartmoor, Mr Holmes?  - No.
那是个神奇的地方  与众不同
It's an amazing place, it's like nowhere else,
虽然荒凉  却很美
it's sort of bleak, but beautiful.
没兴趣  继续说
Not interested. Moving on.
妈妈过世后  我和爸爸常出去散步
We used to go for walks, after my mum died, my dad and me.
每天晚上  我们都会去那片荒原
Every evening, we'd go out onto the moor.
很好  直接跳到你父亲被杀那晚
Yes, good. Skipping to the night that your dad was violently killed,
事发地在哪
where did that happen?
那里有个地方
There's a place,
可以说是个地标  叫恶魔谷
it's a sort of local landmark, called Dewer's Hollow.
那是魔鬼的古称
That's an ancient name for the devil.
然后呢
So?
那晚你们看见魔鬼了吗
Did you see the devil that night?
看见了
Yes.
它体型巨大
It was huge.
煤黑色皮毛  红色眼睛
Coal- black fur with red eyes.
它抓住了他
It got him.
撕扯他  把他撕成了碎片
Tore at him, tore him apart.
其它的我记不起来了
I can't remember anything else.
第二天早上被找到时
They found me the next morning,
我就在荒原上游荡
just wandering on the moor.
我父亲的尸体至今没有找到
My dad's body was never found.
红色眼睛  煤黑皮毛  体型巨大
Red eyes, coal- black fur, enormous...
狗  还是狼
A dog? Wolf?
也许是基因实验产品
Or a genetic experiment.
你是在笑我吗  福尔摩斯先生
Are you laughing at me, Mr Holmes?
怎么  你在开玩笑吗
Why, are you joking?
我父亲一直在怀疑
My dad was always going on about the things
巴斯克维尔的秘密
they were doing at Baskerville.
他们究竟造出了什么样的怪兽
About the type of monsters they were breeding there.
过去别人总是嘲笑他
People used to laugh at him.
至少电视台的人把我说的当回事
At least the TV people took me seriously.
我猜这节目带动了德文郡的旅游业
And I assume did wonders for Devon tourism.
好了...
Yeah...
亨利  无论你父亲发生了什么事
Henry, whatever did happen to your father,
那已经是20年前了
it was 20 years ago.
为什么现在才来找我们
Why come to us now?
我不确定你是不是能帮我
Not sure you can help me,
福尔摩斯先生  你竟然以为这是笑话
Mr Holmes, since you find it all so funny!
因为昨晚发生的事
Because of what happened last night.
什么  昨晚发生了什么事
Why, what happened last night?
你怎么知道
How... How do you know?
我并不知道  我观察到的
I didn't know, I noticed.
你坐德文郡开出的第一班火车过来
You came up from Devon on the first available train this morning.
吃了差劲的早餐  喝了清咖啡
You had a disappointing breakfast and a cup of black coffee.
过道对面的女孩吸引了你
The girl on the seat across the aisle fancied you.
虽然你最初很热情  不过很快又冷淡了
Though initially keen, you've now changed your mind.
而你现在  正急不可待地
You are, however, extremely anxious
想要抽今天的第一支烟
to have your first cigarette of the day.
奈特先生  请坐下抽完这支烟
Sit down, Mr Knight, and do please smoke.
我很乐意你这么做
I'd be delighted.
你到底怎么会注意到这些
How on Earth did you notice all that?
这不重要...
It's not important...
穿孔纸屑证明你被检过票
Punched out holes where your ticket's been checked.
现在不是时候  夏洛克
Not now, Sherlock.
- 我都快憋死了  - 你这是炫耀
- Oh, please, I've been cooped- up for ages!  - You're showing off.
我就是爱炫耀
Of course I am a show- off,
我们这类人就这样
that's what we do.
你用火车上的餐巾擦过溅出的咖啡
Train napkin you used to mop up the spilled coffee.
那污渍表明你没有加牛奶
Strength of the stain shows that you didn't take milk.
上面还有番茄酱渍
There are traces of ketchup on it
在你的嘴角和袖口也有
and on your lips and your sleeve.
英式早点  差不多就是
Cooked breakfast, or the nearest thing
火车上能提供的那些  大概是三明治
those trains can manage. Probably a sandwich.
你怎么知道早餐很差劲
How did you know it was disappointing?
火车上还能有什么
Is there any other type of breakfast on a train?
那女孩
The girl.
女性笔迹很有特点
Female handwriting's distinctive,
纸巾上是她的电话
wrote her phone number down on the napkin.
从书写的角度来看
I can tell from the angle
她写字时面对你
she wrote at that she was sat across from you
还隔着条走道
on the other side of the aisle.
我猜在她下车后不久
Later after she got off, I imagine
你用纸巾擦了洒出来的咖啡
you used the napkin to mop up your spilled coffee,
不小心把号码弄糊了
accidentally smudging the numbers.
你用另一支笔重描了后四位
You've been over the last four digits in another pen,
所以你打算留着号码
so you wanted to keep the number.
可刚才你又用它擦鼻子
Just now you used the napkin to blow your nose,
所以你对她已经没什么兴趣了
so maybe you're not that into her after all.
你颤抖的手指上有
Then there's the nicotine stains on your fingers,
尼古丁熏染的痕迹
your shaking fingers.
我熟悉这种痕迹
I know the signs.
你在火车上没机会抽烟
No chance to smoke when on the train,
打车来这里前也没时间
no time to roll one before you got a cab here.
现在才刚过9点15  你很绝望
It's just after 9.15, you're desperate.
从埃克塞特到伦敦的第一班车5点46发
The first train from Exeter to London leaves at 5.46am.
你坐了第一班车  说明昨晚
You got the first one, so something important
一定发生了很重要的事  没错吧
must have happened last night. Am I wrong?
没错
No.
你说得对
You're right.
一点不差  相当准确
You're completely, exactly right.
见鬼  我早听说过你思维敏捷
Bloody hell, I heard you were quick.
这是我的工作  现在别说了先来一支
It's my job. Now shut up and smoke.
亨利  你父母都去世了
Henry, your parents both died
当时你是七岁左右
and you were what, seven years old?
我想那...
I know, that...
那一定是巨大的创伤
That must be quite a trauma.
你有没有考虑过
Now, have you ever thought
也许是你幻想了这个故事...
that maybe you invented this story, this...
来掩饰这种创伤
to account for it?
莫蒂默医生也这么说
That's what Dr Mortimer says.
谁
Who?
- 他的心理医生  - 我的心理医生
- His therapist.  - My therapist.
显然如此
Obviously.
露易丝・莫蒂默
Louise Mortimer.
她让我回到达特摩尔
She's the reason I came back to Dartmoor.
她觉得我必须面对心魔
She thinks I have to face my demons.
你昨晚回到恶魔谷后
What happened when you went back
发生了什么  亨利
to Dewer's Hollow last night, Henry?
你听了心理医生的话回到那里
You went there on the advice of your therapist
可你现在却来求助咨询侦探
and now you're consulting a detective.
你看到了什么让你改了主意
What did you see that changed everything?
那处山谷很诡异
It's a strange place, the Hollow.
让人内心冰冷  异常恐惧
It makes you feel so cold inside, so afraid.
如果我想读诗
Yes, if I wanted poetry,
我可以读约翰给女友的电邮
I'd read John's emails to his girlfriends,
比这有趣得多  直说你看到什么
much funnier. What did you see?
脚印
Footprints.
就在我看见我父亲被撕碎的地方
On the exact spot where I saw my father torn apart.
男人的还是女人的
Man's or a woman's?
- 都不是  那是...  - 如此而已
- Neither. They were...  - Is that it?
没别的了  脚印  就这些吗
Nothing else? Footprints, is that all?
是的  可那些脚印...
Yes. But they were...
抱歉  莫蒂默医生说对了
No, sorry, Dr Mortimer wins.
用自编的记忆掩盖儿时的心理创伤
It's a childhood trauma masked by an invented memory.
无聊  请吧  奈特先生
Boring. Goodbye, Mr Knight,
谢谢你的烟
thank you for smoking.
可那些脚印呢
What about the footprints?
也许是兽爪印
They're probably paw prints,
什么都可能  也就是什么都没有
could be anything, therefore nothing.
我精神支持你  回去吃点奶油茶点吧
Off to Devon with you and have a cream tea on me.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr Holmes,
那是一头巨型猎犬的脚印
they were the footprints of a gigantic hound.
再说一遍
Say that again.
我看到一些脚印  非常大...
I found footprints, they were big...
不  要你刚才的原话
No, no, no, your exact words.
原样重复你刚才那句话
Repeat your exact words from a moment ago,
要一字不差
exactly as you said them.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr Holmes,
那是一头巨型猎犬的脚印
they were the footprints of a gigantic hound.
- 这案子我接了  - 啥
- I'll take the case. - Sorry, what?
多谢你提醒了我
Thank you for bringing this to my attentions,
- 这里大有文章  - 等会  怎么回事
- it's very promising. - No no no, sorry, what?
刚还说脚印无聊呢  现在又说大有文章
A minute ago, footprints were boring, now they're very promising?
跟脚印无关
It's got nothing to do with footprints,
你就没仔细听  巴斯克维尔  听说过吗
you weren't listening. Baskerville, ever heard of it?
大概吧  相当机密的地方
Vaguely. It's very hush- hush.
- 从那查起准没错  - 你要去吗
- Sounds like a good place to start. - You'll come down then?
不  现在我不能离开伦敦  太忙了
No, I can't leave London at the moment, far too busy.
别担心  我最得力的助手会跑一趟
But don't worry, I'm putting my best man onto it.
靠约翰把相关数据传给我肯定没问题
I can always rely on John to send me the relevant data,
虽然他自己一点都不明白
as he never understands a word of it himself.
什么叫你很忙  你手头根本没案子
What are you talking about you are busy? You don't have a case!
- 你刚还在抱怨...  - 约翰  我有铃兰的案子
- A minute ago you were complaining... - Bluebell, John! I've got Bluebell!
那个无故消失的夜光兔子
The case of the vanishing glow- in- the- dark rabbit.
- 北约都乱成一团了  - 所以你不去了
- NATO's in uproar. - Sorry, you're not coming, then?
好吧
Ok.
你赢了
用不着了  我要去达特摩尔高原
I don't need those any more, I'm going to Dartmoor.
你先去吧  亨利  我们随后就到
You go on ahead, Henry, we'll follow later.
所以你要去
Sorry, so you are coming?
20年前的迷案  巨型猎犬
20- year- old disappearance, a monstrous hound?
绝对不能错过
I wouldn't miss this for the world!
说什么一起游船  你根本不想带我上船
..cruise together, you had no intention of taking me on a boat!
看来赫德森太太终于找到
Looks like Mrs Hudson finally got to
那个在唐卡斯特的老婆了
the wife in Doncaster.
等她发现伊斯兰堡的那个再说吧
Wait until she finds out about the one in Islamabad.
麻烦去帕丁顿车站
Paddington Station, please.
那边是巴斯克维尔
There's Baskerville.
那是格林盆镇
That's Grimpen Village.
那边肯定是...
So that must be...
对  恶魔谷
Yes, Dewer's Hollow.
那是什么
What's that?
雷区吧
A mine field?
严格说巴斯克维尔是个军事基地
Technically, Baskerville's an army base,
我猜他们一直都不准外人入内
so I guess they've always been keen to keep people out.
看来是
Clearly.
对  一天三次  告诉你们朋友  告诉大家
Right, three tours a day. Tell your friends, tell anyone.
非常欢迎各位  记住
Don't be strangers. And remember,
提防猎犬
晚上千万别去旷野上
stay away from the moor at night,
如果你不想死的话  保重
if you value your lives! Take care.
我冷
It's cold.
十字键旅店
精品套房  提供素食
那部分记忆没变
That part doesn't change.
什么变了
What does?
还有别的  是一个词
There's something else. It's a word.
自由
Liberty.
Liberty?
还有个词
And there's another word.
在
In.
IN
I. N.
自由在  这什么意思
Liberty In. What do you think it means?
抱歉不能给你们双人房
Sorry we couldn't do a double room for you boys.
没事  我们不是...
That's fine. We're not...
给
There you go.
- 谢啦  我找你钱  - 谢
- Ta. I'll just get your change. - Ta.
肉类供应
给
There you go.
我注意到
I couldn't help noticing,
那片旷野的地图上  摆着骷髅头
on the map of the moor, a skull and crossbones?
那个啊
That.
- 海盗吗  - 不  叫格林盆大雷区
- Pirates? - No. The Great Grimpen Minefield, they call it.
这样
Right.
不是你想的那样  那是巴斯克维尔试验场
It's not what you think. It's the Baskerville testing site.
有80多年了
It's been going for 80- odd years.
我估计没人知道里面到底有什么
I'm not sure anyone really knows what's there any more.
- 炸弹吗  - 不止是炸弹
- Explosives? - Not just explosives.
他们说闯进那地方
Break into that place and if you're lucky,
被炸死算走运的了
you just get blown up, so they say.
- 免得你散步散到那边  - 谢啦  我会记得
- In case you're planning a wee stroll. - Ta. I'll remember.
嗯  对旅游业有所影响
Aye. No, that buggers up tourism a bit,
多谢那条恶魔猎犬
so thank God for the demon hound.
- 你看那节目了吗  那纪录片  - 前不久看过
- Did you see that show? The documentary? - Quite recently, yeah.
上帝保佑亨利・奈特和那怪物
God bless Henry Knight and his monster from hell.
- 见过吗  那猎犬  - 我吗  没有
- Ever seen it? The hound? - Me? No, no.
弗莱彻见过
Fletcher has.
他会带游人参观
He runs the walks,
参观怪物出没的地方  他见过
the monster walks for the tourists, you know. He's seen it.
这生意不错
That's handy for trade.
比利  我们真是要忙死了
I'm just saying we've been rushed off our feet, Billy.
对  很多怪物猎人
Yeah, lots of monster hunters.
费不了多大事
It don't take much these days,
在推特上一发人就都来了
one mention on Twitter and whoomph!
我们没酒了
We're out of WKD.
- 好  - 又是怪物又是监狱的
- Right. - What with the monster and the ruddy prison,
这我们怎么睡得着
I don't know how we sleep nights.
你呢  盖瑞
Do you, Gary?
- 睡得可死了  - 说瞎话  他打呼噜
- Like a baby.- That's not true. He's a snorer. Hey, ssh.
- 你家那位打呼噜不  - 有薯片不
- Is yours a snorer? - Got any crisps?
行  保重  再见
Yeah. No. All right? Right, take care. Bye.
比赛
介意我坐这么
Mind if I join you?
假的吧  你根本没见过什么猎犬吧
It's not true, is it, you haven't actually seen this hound thing?
- 你是记者么  - 不  绝对不是  就是好奇
- Are you from the papers? - No, nothing like that, just curious.
- 你见过吗  - 大概吧
- Have you seen it? - Maybe.
有证据吗
Got any proof?
我干嘛告诉你  失陪了
Why would I tell you if I did? Excuse me.
- 我给亨利打了电话  - 打赌结束  约翰  抱歉
- I called Henry. - Bet's off John, sorry
- 啥  - 打赌
- What? - Bet?
我的计划得等到天黑才行
My plan needs darkness.
- 还有一个半小时呢  - 等等  什么赌啊
- We've got another half an hour of light. - Wait, wait, what bet?
我跟约翰赌了50英镑
I bet John here 50 quid
说你没法证明你见过猎犬
that you couldn't prove you'd seen the hound.
嗯  酒吧里的人说你可以
Yeah, the guys in the pub said you could.
- 那你就等着输钱吧  老兄  - 是嘛
- Well, you're going to lose your money, mate. - Yeah?
对  我见过
Yeah. I seen it.
就在一个月前  在山谷里
Only about a month ago. Up at the Hollow.
当时有雾  看不太清
It was foggy, mind, couldn't make much out.
- 明白了  没目击者是吧  - 对  但是...
- I see. No witnesses, I suppose. - No, but...
根本没猎犬
Never are.
等等  看那
No, wait. There.
就这样  这叫什么证据
Is that it? It's not exactly proof, is it?
抱歉  约翰  我赢了
Sorry, John, I win.
等等  不仅如此
Wait, wait, that's not all.
人们不喜欢去那里
People don't like going up there, you know.
恶魔谷
To the Hollow.
让他们感觉很不好
Gives them a bad sort of feeling.
是闹鬼了么  这样就想说服我啊
Is it haunted? Is that supposed to convince me?
别傻了  才不是那样
Nah, don't be stupid! Nothing like that.
我估计那确实有什么东西
But I reckon there is something out there.
从巴斯克维尔逃出来的东西
Something from Baskerville, escaped.
- 克隆生物  超级狗  - 也许
- A clone? A super- dog? - Maybe.
谁知道这些年他们排放的气体是啥
God knows what they've been spraying on us all these years,
或者水里放了啥
or putting in the water.
我死活都不会信他们
I wouldn't trust them as far as I could spit.
最多就这样么
Is that the best you've got?
我有个曾在国防部工作的朋友
I had a mate once who worked for the MOD.
某个周末我们约好去钓鱼
One weekend we were meant to go fishing,
他没出现  很晚才过来
but he never showed up. Well, not till late.
他来的时候脸色惨白
When he did, he was white as a sheet.
我到现在都记忆犹新
I can see him now.
"我今天看见些东西  弗莱彻"  他说
"I've seen things today, Fletcher," He said,
"我再也不想见第二次"
"and I never want to see again."
"可怕的东西"
"Terrible things."
他被派去过某个秘密军事基地
He'd been sent to some secret army place.
可能是波顿镇
Porton Down, maybe.
也许是巴斯克维尔  或者其他地方
Maybe Baskerville, or somewhere else.
在那边的秘密实验室里
In the labs there, the really secret labs,
他说他见过可怕的东西
he said he'd seen terrible things.
说老鼠和狗一样大
Rats as big as dogs, he said.
狗呢  和马一样大
And dogs, dogs the size of horses.
50块拿来吧
We did say 50.
谢啦
Ta.
危险
禁止入内
巴斯克维尔
请出示通行证
Pass, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
你还有巴斯克维尔的证件
You've got ID for Baskerville?!
怎么弄的
How?
不是这里的  是我哥哥的证件
It's not specific to this place. It's my brother's.
哪儿都能进  那啥
Access all areas. I, um,
我好久前拿到的  以防万一
acquired it a quiet ages ago. Just in case.
- 这下好了  - 怎么了
- Brilliant. - What's the matter?
- 我们会被逮捕  - 才不会
- We'll get caught. - No, we won't!
- 目前不会  - 五分钟内就会被捕
- Well, not yet. - Caught in five minutes.
"你好  我们就来看看"
"Hi, officially, we come and have a wander
"你们顶级秘密武器基地"
around your top secret weapons base."
"真的  太好了进来吧  水正好开了"
"Really? Great. Come in, kettle's boiled."
会不会被打死还难说呢
That's if we don't get shot.
- 好了  非常感谢  - 谢谢
- Clear. Thanks very much. - Thank you.
一直向前  长官
Straight through, sir.
顶着麦考夫的名字去哪都行
Mycroft's name literally opens doors.
我早说过  他基本就代表了英国政府
I've told you, he practically is the British Government.
我估计在他们发现不对劲之前
I reckon we've got about 20 minutes
我们有20分钟
before they realise something's wrong.
怎么了  有什么问题吗
What is it? Are we in trouble?
请叫我长官
Are we in trouble, sir.
是  长官  对不起  长官
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
你在等我们么
You were expecting us?
看到您的证件信息就立刻过来了  福尔摩斯先生
Your ID showed up straight away, Mr Holmes.
我是莱昂下士  保安人员
Corporal Lyons, security.
有什么问题吗  长官
Is there something wrong, sir?
下士  我希望没有
I hope not, Corporal, I hope not.
这里通常没有人来检查  长官
We don't get inspected here. You see, sir?
太反常了
It just does't happen.
听说过抽查么
Ever heard of a spot check?
约翰・华生上尉
Captain John Watson,
- 诺森伯兰第五燧发枪手团   - 长官好
- Fifth Northumberland Fusiliers. - Sir.
巴里莫尔少校会不高兴  长官
Major Barrymore won't be pleased, sir.
他一定想见您二位
He'll want to see you both.
只怕我们没时间见他  我们要参观一圈
I'm afraid we won't have time for that. We need the full tour.
现在  走吧
Right away. Carry on.
- 这是命令  下士  - 遵命  长官
- That's an order, Corporal. - Yes, sir.
允许进入
请求安全权限
麦考夫・福尔摩斯
最高优先权
干得漂亮
Nice touch.
几百年没把军衔亮出来了
Haven't pulled rank in ages.
- 享受么  - 当然
- Enjoy it? - Yeah.
允许进入
请求安全权限
麦考夫・福尔摩斯
最高优先权
请求安全权限
麦考夫・福尔摩斯
最高优先权
这下面有多少动物
How many animals do you keep down here?
很多  长官
Lots, sir.
有逃走的吗
Any ever escape?
要逃走得学会用电梯  长官
They'd have to know how to use that lift, sir.
我们不会把它们养得那么聪明
We're not breeding them that clever.
除非有人帮忙
Unless they have help.
两位是
And you are?
没事  弗兰克兰博士
It's all right, Dr Frankland,
我带两位先生参观一下
I'm just showing these gentlemen around.
新面孔  真好
New faces, how nice.
不过小心别困在这
Careful you don't get stuck here,though,
我只是过来修龙头
I only came to fix a tap.
那电梯能下几层
How far down does that lift go?
很多层  长官
Quite a way, sir.
下面是什么
And what's down there?
总得有地方放垃圾  长官
Well, we have to keep the bins somewhere, sir.
两位这边请
This way please, gentlemen.
你们在这里都做些什么
So what exactly is it that you do here?
我以为您知道  长官  这不是检查么
I thought you'd know, sir, this being an inspection.
可我不是专家吧
Well, I'm not an expert, am I?
干细胞研究是为了
Everything from stem cell
治愈普通感冒  长官
research to trying to cure the common cold, sir.
现在多用于武器么
But mostly weaponry?
各种武器  是的
Of one sort or another, yes.
生物武器  化学武器
Biological, chemical?
战争是一场接着一场  长官
One war ends, another begins, sir.
总有新的敌人  我们要有所准备
New enemies to fight. We have to be prepared.
安全系统授权中
安全权限
・质询・质询・质询
好  迈克  下次试试H3
OK, Michael, let's try Harlow 3 next time.
- 斯坦佩顿博士  - 斯坦佩顿
- Dr Stapleton... - Stapleton?
怎么
Yes?
这位是谁
Who's this?
最高优先权  女士  上边的命令
Priority ultra, ma'am, orders from on high.
- 他们来检查  - 是吗
- An inspection. - Really?
斯坦佩顿博士  请给予我们应得的尊重
We are to be accorded every courtesy, Dr Stapleton.
你在巴斯克维尔是做什么的
What's your role at Baskerville?
刚也说了要以礼相待吧
Accorded every courtesy, isn't that the idea?
我不能说  政府机密
I'm not free to say. Official secrets.
你绝对能说  我强烈建议你这么做
You most certainly are free, and I suggest you remain that way.
我负责多个项目
I have a lot of fingers in a lot of pies.
原句直译是好几个手指插在好几个馅饼里
我喜欢搞混合
I like to mix things up.
大多数时候是混合基因  有时也会摆弄真手指
Genes, mostly. Now and again, actual fingers.
斯坦佩顿  我就知道我听过你的名字
Stapleton! I knew I knew your name.
我想没有吧
I doubt it.
人们说这世上绝无巧合
People say there's no such thing as coincidence.
他们的生活一定很无聊
Dull lives they must lead.
铃兰
你跟我女儿聊过吗
Have you been talking to my daughter?
为什么要弄死铃兰  斯坦佩顿博士
Why did Bluebell have to die, Dr Stapleton?
- 那只兔子  - 失踪了  而笼子锁着
- The rabbit? - Disappeared from inside a locked hutch,
- 很耳熟吧  - 那只兔子
- which was always suggestive. - The rabbit?
- 显然是被人监守自盗  - 你这么想的吗
- Clearly an inside job. - You reckon?
为什么  因为它在黑暗中会发光吗
Why? Because it glowed in the dark.
我完全不知道你在说什么
I have absolutely no idea what you're talking about.
你是谁
Who are you?
请求安全权限
警报  警报
潜在5级安全漏洞
我想我们就看到这儿了  下士
Well, I think we've seen enough for now, corporal.
- 非常感谢  - 这就完了
- Thank you so much. - That's it?
这就完了  是走这边吧
That's it. It's this way, isn't it?
等等
Just a minute!
我们潜入军事基地就为了调查小兔失踪案吗
Did we just break into a military base to investigate a rabbit?
权限质询
潜在5级安全漏洞
・紧急・紧急・紧急・
涉及人物  麦考夫・福尔摩斯
你在搞什么
麦
用了23分钟  麦考夫动作变慢了
Ha! 23 minutes. Mycroft's getting slow.
又见面了
Hello, again.
- 少校  - 真他妈太过分了
- Major... - This is bloody outrageous!
为什么没人通知我
Why wasn't I told?!
是巴里莫尔少校吧
Major Barrymore, is it?
是啊  不错
Yes, well, good.
很不错  我们很受震动
Very good, we're very impressed.
是不是  福尔摩斯先生
Aren't we, Mr Holmes?
深受震动
Deeply. Hugely.
怎么回事
夏洛克
麦
建立巴斯克维尔就是为了
The whole point of Baskerville was to
- 消除官僚的干扰  - 很抱歉  少校
- eliminate bureaucratic nonsense! - So sorry, Major.
- 检什么察  - 新政策
- Inspections! - New policy.
总不能永远不受监控
Can't remain unmonitored for ever,
天晓得你们会做出什么事来
goodness knows what you'd get up to.
- 别停步  - 长官
- Keep walking. - Sir!
- 他们没有权限  长官  - 什么
- ID unauthorised, sir. - What?
我刚接到一通电话
I've just had the call.
是吗  你们是谁
Is that right? Who are you?
听着  显然是哪里搞错了
Look, there's obviously been some kind of mistake.
显然没有  麦考夫・福尔摩斯
Clearly not, Mycroft Holmes.
是计算机出错了  少校  这都要写进报告里
Computer error, Major. It'll all have to go in the report.
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
没事的  少校  我很清楚这两个人是谁
It's all right, Major, I know exactly who these gentlemen are.
- 是吗  - 是啊  我现在认人有点慢了
- You do? - Yeah, I'm getting a little slow on faces,
不过这位福尔摩斯先生
but Mr Holmes here
我是没想到会在这见到他
isn't someone I expected to show up in this place.
- 这个嘛...  - 很高兴又见面了  麦考夫
- Well... - Good to see you again, Mycroft.
我有幸在世界卫生组织大会上
I had the honour of meeting Mr Holmes
见过福尔摩斯先生  是在布鲁塞尔吧
at the WHO conference in... Brussels, was it?
- 是维也纳  - 维也纳  没错
- Vienna. - Vienna, that's it.
这位正是麦考夫・福尔摩斯  少校
This is Mr Mycroft Holmes, Major.
显然是哪里搞错了
There's obviously been a mistake.
出了事唯你是问  弗兰克兰博士
On your head be it, Dr Frankland.
- 我送他们出去  下士  - 好的  先生
- I'll show them out, Corporal. - Very well, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们是为亨利・奈特来的吧
This is about Henry Knight, isn't it?
我就猜到了
I thought so.
我知道他想找人帮忙  可没想到
I knew he wanted help, but I didn't realise
他会去找夏洛克・福尔摩斯
he was going to contact Sherlock Holmes!
别担心  我知道你们的真实身份
Don't worry, I know who you really are.
我一直看你的网站
I'm never off your website.
不过我以为你会戴那顶帽子呢
I thought you'd be wearing the hat, though.
那不是我的帽子
That wasn't my hat.
他没戴帽子我差点没认出来
I hardly recognise him without the hat.
说了不是我的帽子
It wasn't my hat.
- 你的博客我也很喜欢  华生医生  - 多谢
- I love the blog, too, Dr Watson. - Cheers.
粉色的那起案子
The pink thing.
- 还有铝拐杖那起  - 可不是
- And that one about the aluminium crutch. - Yes.
- 你认识亨利・奈特  - 我跟他父亲更熟
- You know Henry Knight? - Well, I knew his dad better.
他对这里有各种疯狂的看法
He had all sorts of mad theories about this place.
不过他很够朋友
Still, he was a good friend.
听着  我现在真的不方便说话
Listen, I can't really talk now.
这是我的手机号
Here's my cell number.
如果我能帮上亨利  给我打电话
If I can help with Henry, give me a call.
我还没问  弗兰克兰医生
I never did ask, Dr Frankland,
你在这儿到底是做什么的
what exactly is it that you do here?
福尔摩斯先生  我很想告诉你
Mr Holmes, I would love to tell you,
不过  当然啦  那样我就得杀你灭口了
but then, of course, I'd have to kill you.
那你这大话说得可有点太离谱了
That would be tremendously ambitious of you.
跟我说说斯坦佩顿博士
Tell me about Dr Stapleton.
我从不说同事的坏话
I never speak ill of a colleague.
但你也不想说他们好话
But you'd speak well of one, which you're clearly omitting to do.
确实如此  不是吗
I do seem to be, don't I?
- 回头联系你  - 没问题
- I'll be in touch. - Any time.
- 说说吧  - 说什么
- So? - So?
兔子的事是怎么回事
What was all that about the rabbit?
拜托  我们这次别来这套  行不行
Please, can we not do this, this time?
- 哪套  - 你一副神秘莫测的样子  板着脸
- Do what? - You being all mysterious with your... cheekbones,
还竖起大衣领子扮酷
and turning your coat collar up so you look cool.
- 我哪有  - 你就有
- I don't do that. - Yeah, you do.
这么说  柯丝蒂的那封电邮
So, the email from Kirsty.
失踪的夜光兔
The missing luminous rabbit.
柯丝蒂・斯坦佩顿
Kirsty Stapleton,
她妈妈专门搞基因操控
whose mother specialises in genetic manipulation.
她把自己女儿的兔子变成夜光的了
She made her daughter's rabbit glow in the dark?
大概加入了荧光基因
Probably a fluorescent gene.
从别处取出再植入样本体内  现在这不难办到
Removed and spliced into the specimen. Simple enough, these days.
所以呢
So?
所以我们就知道斯坦佩顿博士
So we know that Dr Stapleton
在拿动物进行秘密基因实验
performs secret genetic experiments on animals.
问题在于
The question is,
她有没有拿比兔子更致命的东西做实验
has she been working on something deadlier than a rabbit?
公平地说  这个范围可有点广
To be fair, that is quite a wide field.
请进
Come in, come in.
这房子...
This is...
你...很有钱吗
Are you, um, rich?
- 是啊  - 了解
- Yeah. - Right.
有几个词
There's a couple of words,
我总是看见这几个词
it's what I keep seeing.
自由
Liberty.
Liberty?
自由  还有
Liberty. And...
在
In.
就是这样
It's just that.
你不用了吗
Have you finished?
你想到什么了吗
Mean anything to you?
自由即死亡  是这么说的吧
Liberty in death, isn't that the expression?
死亡才是真正的解脱
The only true freedom.
那现在怎么办
What now, then?
- 夏洛克...有个计划吧  - 是的
- Sherlock's... got a plan? - Yes.
- 好  - 我们带你回荒野去
- Right. - We take you back out onto the moor.
- 好  - 看看有没有东西来袭击你  - 什么
- OK... - And see if anything attacks you. - What?
- 这应该能给我点线索  - 晚上吗
- That should bring things to a head. - At night?
你想要我晚上去那儿吗
You want me to go out there at night?
这就是你的计划吗  真不错
That's your plan? Brilliant!
- 你还有更好的办法吗  - 这不叫计划
- Got any better ideas? - That's not a plan.
约翰  如果那里真有怪兽
If there is a monster out there, John,
我们只能做一件事  找到它的窝
there's only one thing to do. Find out where it lives.
夏洛克...
Sherlock...
UMQRA
UMQRA...
安克拉...
夏洛克
Sherlock...
危险
夏洛克...
Sherlock...
- 我遇见了你的一位朋友  - 什么
- Met a friend of yours? - What?
弗兰克兰博士
Dr Frankland?
鲍勃啊  是啊
Right. Bob, yeah.
他似乎很担心你
He seems pretty concerned about you.
他就是爱操心  保佑他
He's a worrier, bless him.
我回来后他一直对我很好
He's been very kind to me since I came back.
- 他认识你父亲吗  - 对
- He knew your father? - Yeah.
但他在巴斯克维尔工作
But he works at Baskerville.
你父亲不是对那里有意见吗
Didn't your dad have a problem with that?
可朋友到底是朋友  不是吗
Well, mates are mates, aren't they?
瞧瞧你和约翰
I mean, look at you and John.
我们怎么了
What about us?
我是说  他是个挺坦率的人  而你...
Well, I mean, he's a pretty straightforward bloke and you...
鲍勃叔叔和我爸爸说好不谈工作的事
Well, they agreed never to talk about work, Uncle Bob and my dad.
这里就是恶魔谷
Dewer's Hollow.
夏洛克...
Sherlock....
我的天  我的天  我的老天爷啊
My god, my god, my god! My god! My god!
你看见了吗
Did you see it?
你们听见了吗
Did you hear that?
我们看见它了  我们看见了
We saw it. We saw it!
不  我什么都没看见
No, I didn't see anything.
什么  你说什么啊
What? What are you talking about?
我什么都没看见
I didn't see anything.
他肯定看见了
Look, he must have seen it.
我看见了  他肯定也看见了  肯定看见了
I saw it. He must have. He must have.
我...为什么  他为什么要那么说
I... Why? Why? Why would he say that?
它确实在那儿  真的
It was there, it was.
亨利  你得坐下
Henry, Henry, I need you to sit down.
- 请你放松下来  - 我没事  我很好
- Try and relax, please. - I'm OK, I feel OK.
我会给你点帮你入睡的东西  好吗
I'm going to give you something to help you sleep. All right?
这是好事  约翰
This is good news, John.
这...这是好事
It's... it's... it's good.
我没疯
I'm not crazy.
那里确实有猎犬  确实有
There is a hound there, there is.
夏洛克  他也看见了
And Sherlock, he saw it too.
不管他嘴上怎么说  他看见了
No matter what he says, he saw it.
他状态很不好  很狂躁
Well, he's in a pretty bad way. He's manic.
完全坚信有条...
Totally convinced there's some...
超级变种狗在荒野游荡
mutant super- dog roaming the moors.
不过没有这回事  对不对
And there isn't, though, is there?
如果人们在制造超级变种狗
Cos if people knew how to make a mutant super- dog,
我们肯定会知道
we'd know.
肯定会有的买  世道就这样
It'd be for sale. I mean, that's how it works.
听着  在荒野的时候我看见有人打信号
Listen, on the moor I saw someone signalling,
摩尔斯码
Morse.
我猜是摩尔斯码  不过似乎说不太通
I guess it's Morse. It doesn't seem to make much sense.
U  M  Q  R  A  有什么含义吗
U, M, Q, R, A, does that mean anything?
那好吧  我们都掌握了什么情况
So, OK, what have we got?
我们知道有脚印  因为亨利发现了
We know there's footprints, because Henry found them,
那个导游也发现了
and so did the tour guide bloke.
我们听到了什么声音
We all heard something.
或许我们该去找养了条大狗的人
Maybe we should just look for whoever's got a big dog.
- 亨利说得没错  - 什么
- Henry's right. - What?
我也看到了
I saw it, too.
- 什么  - 我也看到了  约翰
- What? - I saw it too, John.
等等  你看到什么了
Just... just a minute, you saw what?
猎犬  就在山谷那里
A hound. Out there in the Hollow.
一条巨大的猎犬
A gigantic hound.
听我说  夏洛克  我们得保持理智
Look, Sherlock, we have to be rational about this.
好了  你
OK, now you,
你是最不该...
of all people, can't just...
我们关注目前了解的情况  好吗
Let's just stick to what we know, yes?
只讲事实
Stick to the facts.
一旦你排除了所有的不可能
Once you've ruled out the impossible,
剩下的不管多么难以置信  一定就是真相
whatever remains, however improbable, must be true.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
瞧瞧我  我害怕了  约翰
Look at me, I'm afraid, John.
居然害怕了
Afraid.
夏洛克
Sherlock.
我一直都冷眼旁观
I've always been able to keep myself distant.
不动感情
Divorce myself from feelings.
可你瞧  我的身体背叛了我
But look, you see, body's betraying me.
有意思  是啊  动感情了
Interesting, yes, emotions.
白璧微瑕  美中不足
The grit on the lens, the fly in the ointment.
好吧
Yeah, all right,
斯波克  放松点
Spock, just... take it easy.
斯波克  星际迷航里的人物  来自高智慧零情感的种族
你最近一直都很兴奋  这你知道
You've been pretty wired lately, you know you have.
我觉得你刚刚走的这趟
I think you've just gone out there
- 把自己搞得有点激动了  - 激动
- and got yourself a bit worked up. - Worked up?
刚刚又黑又吓人
It was dark and scary.
我吗  我什么事都没有
Me? There's nothing wrong with me.
夏洛克
Sherlock...
- 夏洛...  - 我什么事都没有  懂吗
- Sherl... - There is nothing wrong with me! Do you understand!?
你要让我证明吗
You want me to prove it, yes?
我们要找的是条狗  巨大的狗
We're looking for a dog, yes? A great big dog,
你的天才论断  是在找狗[法语]
that's your brilliant theory. Cherchez le chien!
很好  非常棒
Good! Excellent! Yes.
那我们从何开始  从他们如何
Where shall we start? How about them?
伤心的寡妇  和她失业的渔夫儿子
The sentimental widow and her son, the unemployed fisherman.
- 答案是她有狗  - 有吗
- The answer's yes. - Yes?
她养了条西部高原小猎犬  名叫威士忌
She's got a West Highland Terrier called Whisky,
但不是我们要找的目标
not exactly what we're looking for!
- 拜托  - 看他的毛衣  几乎全新
- For God's sake! - Look at his jumper, hardly worn.
显然穿着很不自在
Clearly he's uncomfortable.
可能是因为材质或图案太丑
Could be the material or the hideous pattern,
毛衣应该是别人送的  多半是圣诞礼物
suggests it's a present, probably Christmas.
他想讨母亲欢心  为什么  多半是为钱
He wants into his mother's good books. Why? Probably money.
他请母亲来吃饭  自己那份点的却很少
He's treating her to a meal, but his own portion is small.
是想感动她
He wants to impress her,
却在自己那份上省钱
but he's trying to economise on his own food.
或许他不饿吧
Maybe he's not hungry.
不  小盘前菜  他连盆子都快舔干净了
No, small plate, starter. He's practically licked it clean.
而她连蛋白水果甜饼都没吃完
She's nearly finished her pavlova.
若是她请客  他完全可以放开了吃
If she'd treated him, he'd have had as much as he wanted.
他手头没钱  饥寒交迫
He's hungry and not well- off,
你可以看他的袖口和鞋
you can tell by his cuffs and shoes.
只有母亲会送他那样的圣诞礼物
Only a mother would give him a Christmas present like that.
当然也可能是姑姑或长姐  但母亲最有可能
It could be an aunt or older sister, but mother's more likely.
他曾是渔夫
He was a fisherman,
手上的疤痕很独特  是鱼钩造成
the scarring on his hands is distinctive, fish hooks.
伤疤是很久前的了  说明失业已久
They're old, suggesting long- term unemployment.
这里工业并不发达
Not much industry here,
所以他才找自己的寡母求助
so he's turned to his widowed mother for help.
是寡母吗  当然  明摆着
Widowed? Yes, obviously.
她项链里挂了个男戒
She's got a man's wedding ring on a chain around her neck,
明显是她丈夫的  她自己戴太大了
clearly her late husband's and too big for her finger.
她衣着精致  但首饰都是便宜货
She's well- dressed, but her jewellery is cheap.
她可以戴更好的  但一直留作纪念  多愁善感
She could afford better, but she's kept it, sentimental.
我怎么知道她养狗  她腿上有小细毛
The dog? There are tiny hairs on her leg
但都不超过膝盖
but none above the knees,
说明是条小狗  估计是小猎犬
suggesting it's a small dog, probably a terrier.
是条名叫威士忌的西部高原小猎犬
It is a West Highland Terrier called Whisky.
夏洛克  你怎么会知道
"How do you know that, Sherlock?"
她跟我们同一辆火车过来
She was on the same train as us
我有听到她喊  那不是作弊  而是善于倾听
and I heard her call its name. That's not cheating, that's listening.
我会利用自己的感官  不像某些人  所以我很好
I use my senses, unlike some people, so you see, I am fine.
而且是好得不能再好  所以别吵我了
In fact, I've never been better, so just leave me alone!
好吧
Yeah, OK.
好
Ok.
你干嘛要听我的话
Why would you listen to me?
- 我只是你朋友  - 我没有朋友
- I'm just your friend. - I don't have friends.
没有吗
No.
怪不得没有
I wonder why.
塞尔登先生  你又来了
Mr Selden, you've done it again!
我的皮带老弄不下来
I keep catching it with my belt.
天哪
God!
亨利的心理医生现在在十字键酒馆
夏
那又如何
那有如何
So?
想找她聊聊吗
那又如何
图片下载中. . . . .
你真是太讨厌了
You're a bad man.
真是太刻薄了
That's so mean!
- 再来点酒吗  医生  - 你是要灌醉我吗  医生
- More wine, doctor? - Are you trying to get me drunk, doctor?
怎么可能
The thought never occurred.
因为我刚还以为你在搭讪我
Because a while ago I thought you were chatting me up.
那我是什么时候露的馅
Where did I go wrong?
你开始跟我打听我的病人
When you started asking about my patients.
我是亨利的老朋友
Well, I am one of Henry's oldest friends.
而他是我的病人  我不能说他的事
Yeah, and he's one of my patients, so I can't talk about him.
当然他有跟我提过他的老朋友
Although he has told me about all his oldest friends.
- 你是其中哪位  - 新的那位
- Which one are you? - A new one?
那他父亲呢  他不是你病人了吧
OK, what about his father? He wasn't one of your patients.
他是那种阴谋论疯子...阴谋论专家吗
Wasn't he some sort of conspiracy nutter... theorist?
- 只有你错了才是疯了  - 那他说得对吗
- You're only a nutter if you're wrong. - And was he wrong?
- 我认为他是  - 他念念不忘巴斯克维尔
- I should think so. - But he got fixated on Baskerville, didn't he?
执着于查明那里面到底在做什么
With what they were doing in there.
有没有可能亨利也一样  幻想出一条猎犬
Couldn't Henry have gone the same way, started imagining a hound?
为什么你觉得我会谈这些
Why do you think I'll talk about this?
因为我觉得你很担心他
Because I think you're worried about him
因为我也是医生
and because I'm a doctor too.
因为我另外一位朋友
And because I have another friend
他可能也有了同样的问题
who might be having the same problem.
华生医生
Dr Watson!
调查进展如何了
How's the investigation going?
什么  什么调查
What, investigation?
你不知道吗  你没看过那个博客吗  夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Didn't you know? Don't you read the blog? Sherlock Holmes.
- 是这样  - 夏洛克什么
- It's... - Sherlock who?
- 私人侦探  这位是他的私人助理  - 私人助理
- Private detective. This is his PA. - PA?
- 同居在一起的私人助理  - 很好
- Well, live- in PA. - Perfect!
同居
Live- in..?
这位是莫蒂默医生  亨利的心理医生
This is Dr Mortimer, Henry's therapist.
你好  我是鲍勃・弗兰克兰
Hello. Bob Frankland.
告诉夏洛克  我会盯着斯坦佩顿
Listen, tell Sherlock I've been keeping an eye on Stapleton.
他想找我聊随时都可以  好吗
Any time he wants a little chat. All right?
何不请他喝一杯  他好像很喜欢你
Why don't you buy him a drink? I think he likes you.
早  睡得好吗
Morning! How are you feeling?
我
I...
- 睡得不好  - 真可惜
- I didn't sleep very well. - That's a shame.
我来泡点咖啡吧  看  你房子渗水了
Shall I make us some coffee? Look, you've got damp!
听着  昨晚...
Listen, last night...
你为什么说自己什么都没看到
Why did you say you hadn't seen anything?
- 我明明看到那条猎犬  但  - 是猎犬吗
- I mean, I only saw the hound for a minute, but... - Hound?
- 什么  - 你为什么要说它是猎犬
- What? - Why do you call it a hound? Why a hound?
- 你什么意思  - 很奇怪吧
- Why? What do you mean? - It's odd, isn't it?
你选这词很奇怪  年代久远了
It's a strange choice of words, archaic.
所以我才接了这案子
That's why I took the case.
福尔摩斯先生  那是头巨型猎犬的脚印
"Mr Holmes, they were the footprints of a gigantic hound."
为什么要说"猎犬"
Why say "Hound"?
我不知道  我从没...
I don't know, I've never...
咖啡还是算了吧
Actually, I'd better skip the coffee.
那摩斯电码有头绪了吗
Did you get anywhere with that Morse code?
U M Q R A  是这样吗  安克拉
U, M, Q, R, A, wasn't it? Umqra.
没什么
Nothing.
算了吧  我以为自己发现了什么  其实不是
Look, forget it. I thought I was onto something, I wasn't.
- 确定吗  - 确定
- Sure? - Yeah.
- 露易丝・莫蒂默那边呢  有什么发现吗  - 没有
- How about Louise Mortimer, did you get anywhere with her? - No.
太糟糕了  但你这边有什么消息吗
Too bad. But did you get any information?
你现在幽默多了
You're being funny now?
说不定能打破点僵局呢
Thought it might break the ice, a bit.
幽默不适合你  还是冷一点好
Funny doesn't suit you. Let's stick to ice.
- 约翰  - 我没事
- John... - It's fine.
等等  昨晚的事...
Wait, what happened last night...
是因为我有了前所未有的感觉
something happened to me something I've not experienced before.
你说了  你害怕了  夏洛克・福尔摩斯害怕了
Yes, you said. Fear, Sherlock Holmes got scared, you said.
不仅如此  约翰  是我开始怀疑了
It was more than that, John. It was doubt.
我感觉到怀疑
I felt doubt.
我一直能相信自己的感觉
I've always been able to trust my senses,
相信眼见为实的证据  直到昨晚
the evidence of my own eyes, until last night.
你不能相信自己看到了某种怪物
You can't actually believe that you saw some kind of monster?
是  我不相信
No, I can't believe that.
但我确实看到了  所以问题是  怎么会看到
But I did see it, so the question is, how? How?
是啊
Yes.
很好
Yeah, right, good.
这么说你有头绪了  祝好运
So you've got something to go on, then. Good luck with that.
约翰  我之前说的话  是真心的
Listen, what I said before, John, I meant it.
我没有朋友
I don't have friends.
身边就只有你
I've just got one.
好吧
Right.
约翰
John.
约翰  你简直太神奇太了不起了
John! You are amazing! You are fantastic!
我知道了  你不用这么夸张
Yes, all right, you don't have to overdo it.
你或许不是发光的人
You may not be the most luminous of people,
但你是传递光的人  无与伦比
but as a conductor of light, you are unbeatable.
多谢  什么
Cheers. What?
有些人不是天才
Some people who aren't geniuses
却有着激发天才的非凡能力
have an amazing ability to stimulate it in others.
你刚不在道歉呢嘛  别这么快就扫兴好吗
You were saying sorry a minute ago. Don't spoil it.
我做什么了  这么能激发人
So what have I done that's so bloody stimulating?
猎犬
什么
Yeah?
如果这不是一个词  而是单独的字母呢
What if it's not a word, what if it is individual letters?
你觉得这个是首字母缩写词吗
You think it's an acronym?
完全没头绪  不过...
Absolutely no idea, but...
你在这里搞什么鬼
What the hell are you doing here?!
我也很高兴见到你
Nice to see you too
- 我在度假  你信吗  - 我不信
- I'm on holiday, would you believe? - No, I wouldn't.
- 你好  约翰  - 格雷格
- Hello, John. - Greg.
听说你们在这边  忙什么呢
I heard you were in the area. What are you up to?
追查电视里说的那条地狱犬吗
Are you after this Hound of Hell, like on the telly?
你还没解释呢  探长  你为什么会在这里
I'm waiting for an explanation, Inspector, why are you here?
我说过了  我在度假
I've told you, I'm on holiday.
你晒得这么黑
You're brown as a nut.
明显是刚度假回来
You're clearly just back from your holidays.
我还想再度一个
I fancied another one.
是麦考夫搞的鬼吧  当然是了
This is Mycroft, isn't it? Of course it is.
听到巴斯克维尔出了事
One mention of Baskerville
就派我的监护人来暗中监视我  还用化名
and he sends down my handler to spy on me, incognito.
- 所以你才自称什么"格雷格"  - 他本来就叫那个名字
- Is that why you're calling yourself "Greg"? - That's his name.
- 是吗  - 没错  你压根就没关心过吧
- Is it? - Yes. If you'd ever bothered to find out.
听好  我不是你的监护人
Look, I'm not your handler.
我只是被你哥哥使唤惯了
And I just do what your brother tells me.
- 事实上  你来得正好  - 为什么
- Actually, you could be just the man we want. - Why?
我可没闲着  夏洛克
Well, I've not been idle, Sherlock.
我可能找到了点线索  这里
I think I might have found something. Here.
我之前不知道是不是有关系
I didn't know if it was relevant.
不过现在看上去似乎有点意思
Starting to look like it might be.
素食餐厅  可用不了这么多肉啊
That is an awful lot of meat for a vegetarian restaurant.
太棒了
Excellent.
有了亲切又恐怖的苏格兰场探长
A nice, scary inspector from Scotland Yard,
只要几通电话就能摆平  超便利
who can put in a few calls, might come in very handy.
点单
Shop.
这是什么
What's this?
- 咖啡  我泡了咖啡  - 你从来不泡咖啡
- Coffee. I made coffee. - You never make coffee.
- 你不想喝吗  - 你不用没完没了地道歉
- Don't you want it? - You don't have to keep apologising.
谢谢
Thanks.
我不加糖
I don't take sugar.
这些记录可追溯到将近两个月前
These records go back nearly two months.
很好喝  很香
That's nice. It's good.
你们是在电视播出后  想到这主意的吗
Is that when you had the idea, after the TV show went out?
是我  是我的错
It's me. It was me.
抱歉  盖瑞  我忍不住
I'm sorry, Gary. I couldn't help it.
我在卡尔婚礼上吃了个熏肉三明治
I had a bacon sandwich at Cal's wedding
- 然后就一发不可收拾了  - 好借口
- and one thing led to another. - Nice try.
我们只是想办法
Look, we were just trying to
添油加醋了一番  好吗
give things a bit of a boost, you know?
荒野里有条失踪的大狗
Let a great big dog run wild up on the moor,
简直是天赐良机
it was heaven- sent.
就像我们有了自己的尼斯湖水怪
It was like us having our own Loch Ness monster.
你们把它关在哪
And where do you keep it?
那边有个老矿井  不太远
There's an old mine shaft. It's not too far.
- 它本来在那挺好  - 本来
- He was all right there. - Was?
我们控制不住那畜生了
We couldn't control the bloody thing.
它实在太凶残
It was vicious.
然后  一个月前
And then, a month ago,
比利带它去了兽医那里  然后...
Billy took him to the vet and, you know...
它死了吗
He's dead?
我们杀了它
Put down.
对  我们别无选择
Yeah. No choice.
一切都结束了
So it's over.
这只是个玩笑
It was just a joke, you know.
是啊  很好笑
Yeah, hilarious
你们差点把一个人逼疯掉
You've nearly driven a man out of his mind.
其实他很高兴你来了
You know he's actually pleased you're here?
偷偷高兴着呢
Secretly pleased.
是吗
Is he?
不错
That's nice.
估计他就是喜欢所有熟人凑在一起
I suppose he likes having all the same faces back together.
- 以满足他的...  - 阿斯伯格综合症吗
- Appeals to his... his... - Asperger's?
自闭症的一种  一般被认为是没有智能障碍的自闭症
你相信他们杀掉那条狗了吗
So, you believe them about having the dog destroyed?
没理由不相信
No reason not to.
希望没造成什么伤害
Well, hopefully there's no harm done.
我也不确定该以什么罪名起诉他们
I'm not quite sure what I'd charge them with, anyway.
先跟本地警方谈谈再说
I'll have a word with the local force.
好  就这样吧  回头见
Right, that's that, then. Catch you later.
我很喜欢这里
I'm enjoying this.
伦敦的污浊气一扫而空的感觉真好
It's nice to get London out of your lungs.
人们在荒野上看到的就是他们的狗吗
So that was their dog that people saw out on the moor?
貌似是的
Looks like it.
但不是你看到的那条  那不是普通的狗
But that wasn't what you saw, that wasn't just an ordinary dog.
没错  它体型庞大
No. It was immense.
目如赤焰  还在发光  约翰
It had burning red eyes, and it was glowing, John,
它全身都在发光
its whole body was glowing.
我有个猜想
I've got a theory,
但还得回巴斯克维尔验证一下
but I need to get back into Baskerville to test it.
怎么去  上次的把戏不能再用了
How? Can't pull off the ID trick again.
也没必要再用
Might not have to.
喂  亲爱的哥哥  你好吗
Hello, brother, dear. How ARE you?
下午好  先生  请关闭引擎
Afternoon, sir. Can you turn the engine off?
谢谢
Thank you.
我一进去就得去找巴里莫尔少校
I need to see Major Barrymore as soon as we get inside.
- 好的  - 所以
- Right. - Which means
- 你来找那条猎犬  - 好
you'll have to start the search for the hound. - OK.
在实验室找  先找斯坦佩顿那里
In the labs. Stapleton's first.
可能会很危险
It could be dangerous.
你也知道我很乐意
Oh, you know I'd love to.
我当然乐意让你在这里为所欲为
I'd love to give you unlimited access to this place.
为什么不呢
Why not?
这个请求很简单  少校
It's a simple enough request, Major.
我可从没听过这么荒谬的说法
I've never heard of anything so bizarre.
你要给我24小时
You're to give me 24 hours,
- 这是说定了的  - 一秒也不许多待
- it's what I negotiated. - Not a second more.
我不得不服从命令
I may have to comply with this order,
但我不必非要喜欢
but I don't have to like it.
我不明白你究竟想在这找到什么
I don't know what the hell you expect to find here, anyway.
- 或许是真相  - 什么真相
- Perhaps the truth. - About what?
我懂了
Oh, I see.
瞧你这身打扮  我早该看出来
The big coat should have told me.
你也是个相信阴谋论的家伙吧
You're one of the conspiracy lot, aren't you?
那好  去吧  发掘真相吧
Well, then, go ahead, seek them out,
什么怪物  致命射线  外星人
the monsters, the death rays, the aliens.
你这有这些东西吗
Have you got any of those?
我就是好奇而已
Oh, just wondering.
有两个  60年代在这里坠机了
A couple. Crash landed here in the '60s.
我们叫它们两傻组合
We call them Abbott and Costello.
两傻组合  喜剧演员
善于恶搞惊悚题材
祝你好运  福尔摩斯先生
Good luck, Mr Holmes.
天啊
God!
请勿靠近  除非你想感冒
天啊
Oh. God. Ow.
禁止通行
拜托了
Come on.
禁止通行
有人吗
Hello?
别  拜托了  拜托了
No, come on. Come on.
多幼稚  别胡思乱想
Naive. Don't be ridiculous.
接电话呀
Pick up.
该死
Damn it.
好吧
Right.
它在这儿  跟我在一个房间里
It's here. It's in here with me.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
把我救出去  夏洛克  你得救我出去
Get me out, Sherlock, you've got to get me out.
我在大实验室  我们看的第一个实验室
The big lab, the first lab that we saw.
约翰  约翰
John... John?
现在就来  夏洛克  求你了
Now, Sherlock! Please!
好  我这就来找你  你接着说话
All right, I'll find you. Keep talking.
不行  它会听到我
I can't, it'll hear me.
接着说  你看到什么了
Keep talking. What are you seeing?
- 约翰  - 我听着呢
- John? - Yes, I'm here.
你看见什么了
What can you see?
我不知道  但我能听见它的声音
I don't know. I don't know, but I can hear it now.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
冷静  保持冷静  你能看见它吗
Stay calm, stay calm. Can you see it?
你能看见它吗
Can you see it?
不能
No.
我看见它了
I can see it.
它在这儿
It's here. It's here.
你还好吗  约翰
Are you all right? John?
我的老天  就是那条猎犬
Jesus Christ! It was the hound!
夏洛克  它就在这  我发誓
Sherlock, it was here, I swear it,
夏洛克  它肯定是...
Sherlock, it must, it must...
你看见它了吗  你肯定看见了
Did- did you see it? You must have!
没事了  现在没事了
It's all right, it's OK now.
不  才怪  怎么会没事
No, it's not! It's not ok!
我看见它了  之前是我错了
I saw it, I was wrong!
- 别急着下结论  - 什么
- Well, let's not jump to conclusions. - What?
你看见什么了
What did you see?
我说过了  我看到那条猎犬了
I told you, i saw the hound.
- 体型巨大  目如赤焰  - 没错
- Huge, red eyes? - Yes.
- 发着光  - 是的
- Glowing? - Yeah.
- 不  - 什么
- No. - What?
发光那部分是我编的
I made up the bit about glowing.
你听过我的描述  所以以为自己看到了
You saw what you expected to see because I told you.
你被下了药  我们都中招了
You have been drugged. We have all been drugged.
下药
Drugged?
- 你还能走吗  - 当然
- Can you walk? - Of course I can walk.
来吧  是时候摆平这妖孽了
Come on, then. It's time to lay this ghost.
又来了
Oh, Back again?
这次又是为什么
What's on your mind this time?
这是谋杀  斯坦佩顿医生
Murder, Dr Stapleton.
精心策划  冷血无情的谋杀
Refined, cold- blooded murder.
是你来为小柯丝蒂揭开
Will you tell little Kirsty
铃兰的失踪之谜呢  还是我来
what happened to Bluebell, or shall I?
好吧  你究竟想怎样
OK. What do you want?
能借你显微镜一用吗
Can I borrow your microscope?
氢
水
你真的没事吗
Are you sure you're OK?
你看起来很憔悴
You look very peaky.
不  我很好
No, I'm all right.
是水母的绿色荧光蛋白基因
It was the GFP gene from a jellyfish,
要是你好奇的话
in case you're interested.
什么
What?
- 让兔子发亮的  - 对  没错
- In the rabbits. - Right, yeah.
基因取自水晶水母  如果你想知道的话
Aequorea victoria, if you really want to know.
- 为什么这么做  - 为什么不呢
- Why? - Why not?
我们现在不想这种问题  试验还没完成
We don't ask questions like that here. It isn't done.
总之这是个基因混合体
It was a mix- up, anyway.
我发现女儿的宠物竟是试验样品
My daughter ended up with one of the lab specimens,
可怜的铃兰不得不消失了
so poor Bluebell had to go.
- 你可真够慈悲  - 我知道
- Your compassion is overwhelming! - I know.
有时我也讨厌自己这一点
I hate myself sometimes.
那好  你可以信任我  我也是个医生
So, come on, then, you can trust me, I'm a doctor,
你这还藏了什么不可告人的东西
what else have you got hidden away up here?
听着  你好好想想
Listen, if you can imagine it,
其他地方可能也有人从事这种研究
someone is probably doing it somewhere.
这是肯定的
Of course they are.
克隆吗
Cloning?
当然  克隆羊多利  还记得吗
Yes, of course. Dolly the Sheep, remember?
- 克隆人呢  - 有何不可
- Human cloning? - Why not?
还有什么克隆动物  除了羊
And what about animals? Not sheep.
大型的动物
Big animals.
体型大小不难控制  小菜一碟
Size isn't a problem. Not at all.
唯一的约束就是伦理与法律
The only limits are ethics and the law and
但这些都可以变通
both those things can be very flexible.
但在这不是  在巴斯克威尔不是
But not here, not at Baskerville.
老天  什么都没有  说不通呀
Jesus! Nothing there! It doesn't make any sense!
你以为能找到什么
What were you expecting to find?
当然是某种药物  肯定有某种药物
A drug, of course. It has to be a drug.
可以引发幻觉或精神错乱之类
An hallucinogenic or a deliriant of some kind.
糖里什么都没有
There's no trace of anything in the sugar.
- 糖  - 糖  是的
- Sugar? - Sugar, yes.
简单的排除法
A simple process of elimination.
我看到了猎犬  当然那是我的幻觉
I saw the hound, saw it as my imagination expected me to see it.
让我以为那是个转基因怪物
A genetically engineered monster.
我知道自己看到的是假象
I knew I couldn't believe the evidence with my eyes,
所以可能有七种解释
so there were seven possible reasons for it,
最有可能的一种就是药物影响
the most possible being narcotics.
亨利・奈特  他也看见了
Henry Knight, he saw it too,
但你没有  约翰  你没看见
but you didn't, John. You didn't see it.
自从来到格林盆  我们吃的喝的
We have eaten and drunk exactly the same things
都一模一样  只有一个例外
since we got to Grimpen, apart from one thing.
- 你喝咖啡不加糖  - 懂了  然后呢
- You don't take sugar in your coffee. - I see, so?
我从亨利的厨房里拿了点糖
I took it from Henry's kitchen, his sugar.
但它完全没问题
It's perfectly all right.
- 或许并非药物所致  - 不  肯定是
- But maybe it's not a drug. - No, it has to be a drug.
药物究竟是如何进入我们的身体
How did it get into our systems? How?
肯定有些什么东西
There has to be something, something...
一些
Something...
一些藏得很深的线索
Something buried deep.
- 出去  - 什么
- Get out. - What?
出去  我要进入我的思维殿堂
Get out, I need to go to my mind palace.
你的什么
Your what?
这种时候他会变得少言寡语
He's not going to be doing much talking for a while,
我们还是出去吧
we may as well go.
- 他的什么  - 他的思维殿堂
- His what? - His "Mind Palace".
这是一种记忆方式  一种思维地图
It's a memory technique, a sort of mental map.
你在地图上绘制地点
You plot a map with a location,
不必是真实的地点
it doesn't have to be a real place.
把记忆存储在那里
You deposit memories there.
理论上来说  这样你什么都不会遗忘
Theoretically, you never forget anything.
只要找对途径  就能找回记忆
All you do is find your way back to it.
所以这种意念化地点可以是任何场所
So this imaginary location could be anything,
- 比方一座房子或一条街  - 是的
- a house or a street? - Yeah.
可他说是"殿堂"  他说那是殿堂
But he said "palace", he said it was a palace?
是啊  他就这德性  还能咋样
Yeah, well, he would, wouldn't he?
猎犬
自由
钟声
博爱
模式
自由
钟声
博爱
模式
自由
钟声
博爱
模式
自由
钟声
博爱
模式
自由
自由百货公司
伦敦
自由
自由  平等  博爱
钟声
约翰・菲利普・苏萨[作曲家]
自由钟声进行曲[美国军乐]
自由
在
旅馆
印度
因戈尔施塔特[德]
铟原子数=49
脊背犬
猎狼犬
猎犬[猫王名曲]
你什么都不是
You ain't nothing...
自由
在
猎犬
Hound.
自由城
印第安纳州
H.O.U.N.D[猎犬]
我的天
Oh, my god!
我的天  我很抱歉  真的很抱歉
Oh my god! Oh my god! I am so... I am so sorry. I am so sorry.
- 约翰  - 我守着门呢
- John? - Yeah, I'm on it.
猎犬计划
Project HOUND.
我肯定在哪看到过  记下来过
I must have read about it, stored it away.
中情局在印第安纳州自由城进行的试验
An experiment in a CIA facility in Liberty, Indiana.
用户名
密码
输入搜索关键词■
H- o- u- n- d
H- o- u- n- d.
搜索中
获取失败  中情局机密
域名转移密码
恐怕我的权限不够
That's as far as my access goes, I'm afraid.
肯定还有途径  比方说密码
There must be an override, a password?
我想是的  但只有巴里莫尔少校知道
I imagine so, but that'd be Major Barrymore's.
密码  密码  密码
Password, password. Password.
他是坐在这里想出的密码
He sat here when he thought it up.
跟我描述一下他
Describe him to me?
- 你见过他  - 我要你描述他
- You've seen him. - But describe him.
他恪守纪律  厚古薄今
He's a bloody martinet, a throw- back,
是能够被委以重任的人物
the sort they'd have sent into Suez.
很好  老派人物  传统主义者
Good, excellent, old- fashioned. Traditionalist.
他不会用孩子的名字当密码
Not the sort to use his children's name as a password.
给爸爸的画
他热爱这份工作  为之骄傲
He loves his job, proud of it.
密码一定与工作相关
This is work- related.
那么他视线里有什么
So what's at eye level?
巴斯克维尔
欲进入该机构必须有书面批准
科学实验动物法  1986年
巴斯克维尔安全事务
书籍
Books.
《简氏防务周刊》  装订版
Jane's Defence Weekly, bound copies.
《汉尼拔》
Hannibal.
威灵顿  隆美尔
Wellington. Rommel.
丘吉尔著的《英语国家史》  共四卷
Churchill's History of the english- Speaking Peoples, all four volumes.
温斯顿・丘吉尔
英语国家史
丘吉尔  他喜欢丘吉尔
Churchill, he's fond of Churchill.
《唐宁街岁月》  一共五本
Copy of The Downing Street Years, one to five.
玛格丽特・撒切尔
唐宁街岁月
治国才能
好几本撒切尔的传记
Separate biographies of Thatcher.
19世纪80年代中期  应该是他父亲
Mid- 1980s, at a guess. Father and son.
老巴里莫尔  很多勋章  金十字英勇勋章
Barrymore Senior, medals, Distinguished Service Order.
那个日期  应该是马岛战争的老兵
That date, I'd say Falklands veteran.
对  这么说撒切尔比丘吉尔更有可能
Right, Thatcher's a more likely bet than Churchill.
那是密码吗
That's the password?
不是  巴里莫尔少校这种男人
No! With a man like Major Barrymore,
他只有可能用名字来做密码
only first name terms would do.
获取失败  中情局机密
域名转移密码
玛
葛
丽
特
获取失败  中情局机密
域名转移密码
玛格丽特[撒切尔夫人的名字]
允许访问
下载中
极易受暗示
恐惧和刺激
条件反射的恐惧
气态传播
莱纳德・汉森
杰克・奥玛拉
伊莲・迪森
玛丽・乌斯洛斯基
瑞克・奈德
猎犬
Hound.
偏执  妄想
大脑额叶严重损伤
血脑
危险的加速
总颅外伤
多起凶杀案
上帝啊
Jesus.
猎犬计划
Project HOUND.
一种新型毒药  能让吃了药的人极易受到暗示
A new deliriant drug which rendered its users incredibly suggestible.
他们想将其用作针对人的武器
They wanted to use it as an anti- personnel weapon,
利用恐惧和刺激彻底扰乱敌人的心智
to totally disorientate the enemy using fear and stimulus.
但这个项目在1986年就被关闭和掩盖了
But they shut it down and hid it away in 1986.
因为那些药物对被试的影响
Because of what it did to the subjects they tested it on.
还有他们对其他人的所作所为
And what they did to others.
长期的药物作用把他们逼疯了
Prolonged exposure drove them insane.
他们变得异常狂暴  无法控制
Made them almost uncontrollably aggressive.
那么说有人又在研究了吗  继续这项试验
So, someone's been doing it again? Carrying on the experiments?
- 也许是想改进这种药物  20多年了  - 是谁
- Attempting to refine it, perhaps. For the last 20 years. - Who?
这些名字你有印象吗
Those names mean anything to you?
不  没印象
No, not a thing.
五名主要科学家
Five principal scientists.
20年前
20 years ago.
也许是这张照片后面的某个人
Maybe our friend's somewhere in the back of the picture?
他现在年纪应该比较大了
Someone old enough to be there
因为他1986年的时候就在了
at the time of the experiments in 1986?
也许他说过"手机"[英国不用cell表示手机]
Maybe somebody who says "Cell phone"
因为他在美国呆过  记得吗  约翰
Because of time spent in America? You remember, John?
这是我的手机号码
Here's my, cell number.
他给了我们他的号码  让我们有需要就联系他
He gave us his number, in case we needed him.
天啊  是鲍勃・弗兰克兰
My god, Bob Frankland.
但鲍勃不研究这个  他是病毒学家
But Bob doesn't work on... He's a virologist.
这是化学武器
This is chemical warfare.
但这是他起步的地方
That's where he started, though.
他一直都坚信不疑
He's never lost the certainty,
坚信这种药物肯定能成功
the obsession that that drug really could work.
幸好他给了我们他的手机
Nice of him to give us his number.
我们和他碰个头吧
Let's arrange a little meeting.
猎犬计划
印第安纳州  自由城
喂
Hello?
- 你是谁  - 你们得去找亨利
- Who's this? - You've got to find Henry.
是露易丝・莫蒂默
It's Louise Mortimer.
露易丝  怎么了
Louise, what's wrong?
亨利他刚在回想当时的情景  然后他...
Henry was, was remembering. Then...
他想要...
He tried...
- 他有枪  他拿着枪跑了  他想...  - 什么
- He's got a gun, he went for the gun and tried to... - What?
他跑了  但你得阻止他
He's gone. But you've got to stop him,
我不知道他会做出什么事来
I don't know what he might do.
你在哪儿
Where, where are you?
我在他家  我没事
His house. I'm OK. I'm OK.
好的  在那别动  我会让人去找你  好吗
Right, stay there. We'll get someone to you, OK?
- 是亨利吗  - 他袭击了她  - 他跑了吗
- Henry? - He's attacked her. - Gone?
他只会去那里  这一切开始的地方
There's only one place he'll go, back to where it started.
雷斯垂德  快去山谷
Lestrade? Get to the Hollow.
恶魔谷  快  带上枪
Dewer's Hollow, now! And bring a gun.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起  爸爸
I'm so sorry, Dad.
- 不  亨利  别这样  - 别过来
- No, Henry, no, no! - Get back!
- 离我远点  - 别紧张  亨利  放松
- Get away from me! - Easy, Henry, easy. Just relax.
我知道我是谁  我知道我要做什么
I know what I am, I know what I tried to do.
- 把枪放下  没事了  - 不  我知道我是谁
- Just put the gun down, it's OK. - No, no! I know what I am!
是的  你当然知道  亨利
Yes, I'm sure you do, Henry.
这一切都能解释得通了吧
It's all been explained to you, hasn't it?
- 非常清楚了  - 什么
- Explained very carefully. - What?
有人要让你闭嘴
Someone needed to keep you quiet,
让你走不出童年的阴影
needed to keep you as a child,
让你再次被当年的噩梦折磨
to reassert the dream you both clung on to,
因为你开始想起来了
because you had started to remember.
快想起来  亨利  你必须想起来
Remember now, Henry, you've got to remember
你小时候这里究竟发生了什么
what happened here when you were a little boy.
我觉得它抓住了我爸爸
I thought it had got my dad.
那条猎犬  我以为...天啊
The hound. I thought... Jesus!
我不...我什么都不知道了  不知道
I don't... I don't know any more! I don't!
不  亨利  求你了
No, Henry! Henry, for God's sake!
亨利  再想想  "自由"  "在"  这两个词
Henry, remember. "Liberty In." Two words.
20年前一个吓坏了的孩子看到的两个词
Two words a frightened little boy saw here 20 years ago.
这样你就能想明白一切
You'd started to piece things together.
想起那天晚上发生了什么事
Remember what happened here that night.
其实不是动物吧  亨利
It wasn't an animal, was it, Henry?
不是个怪物
Not a monster.
而是个人
A man.
你还只是个孩子  你接受不了
You couldn't cope. You were just a child.
所以你把它解释成很奇怪的东西
So you rationalised it into something very different.
但你开始想起来了  有人要阻止你
Then you started to remember, so you had to be stopped.
把你逼疯
Driven out of your mind
这样就没人会相信你说的话
so that no- one would believe a word that you said.
夏洛克
Sherlock!
没事的
It's OK.
没事了  伙计
It's OK, mate.
但我们看到了猎犬  那天晚上  我们都看到了
But we saw it, the hound, last night. We did, we s...
不  是有条狗  亨利
No, but there was a dog, Henry,
留下脚印  惊吓路人
leaving footprints, scaring witnesses,
但那不过是条普通的狗
but nothing more than an ordinary dog.
因为我们中毒了  所以我们的想象变成了事实
We both saw it, saw it as our drugged minds wanted us to see it.
恐惧和刺激  就是这么回事
Fear and stimulus, that's how it works.
但其实根本就没有什么怪物
But there never was any monster.
夏洛克
Sherlock?
- 不  不要  - 亨利  - 夏洛克
- No! No, no, no, no! - Henry, Henry... - Sherlock!
不  不要
No, no! No, no, no, noooo!
亨利
Henry.
夏洛克  你看到了吗
Sherlock, are you seeing this?
好吧  他没被下药  夏洛克  那是什么
Right, he is not drugged, Sherlock, so what's that?
- 不  - 到底是什么
- No! - What is it?!
好吧  它还在这儿
All right, it's still here.
但只是条狗  亨利
But it's just a dog, Henry.
一条普通的狗罢了
It's nothing more than an ordinary dog.
上帝啊
My god!
老天爷
Christ!
不
No. No!
不是你  不可能是你
It's not you, not you!
- 是烟雾  - 什么  - 是这里的雾  雾里有毒
- The fog. - What? - It's the fog, the drug, it's in the fog!
气态传播  记录里就是这么写的
Aerosol dispersant, that's what it said in the records.
猎犬计划  是雾
Project HOUND, it's the fog!
化学雷区
A chemical minefield.
老天爷  快杀了它
For God's sake, kill it! Kill it!
看看  亨利
Look at it, Henry.
- 不  - 快看
- No, no, no. - Come on, look at it!
你个混蛋
You bastard.
王八蛋
You... bastard!
- 20年了  我白白痛苦了20年  - 现在都结束了
- 20 years! 20 years of my life, making no sense! - It's all over now, come on.
为什么你不直接杀了我
Why didn't you just kill me?
因为死人反而会引起疑心
Because dead men get listened to,
他的目的不是要杀你
he needed to do more than kill you.
他必须摧毁你父亲所说的一切
He had to discredit every word you ever said about your father.
而他的武器就在他脚下
And he had the means right at his feet.
化学雷区  地底下的压力垫
A chemical minefield, pressure pads in the ground,
你每次回到这里  都会对你下药
dosing you up every time that you came back here.
既是凶器也是犯案现场
Murder weapon and scene of the crime all at once.
这个案子真是  太谢谢你了  亨利
This case, Henry. Thank you.
- 简直太妙了  - 夏洛克  - 啥
- It's been brilliant! - Sherlock. - What?
注意场合
Timing.
- 不合适吗  - 不  没事
- Not good? - No, no, it's OK.
没关系  因为这意味着
It's fine. Because this means...
这意味着我父亲说的没错
this means that my dad was right.
他确实发现了秘密
He'd found something out, hadn't he?
所以你杀了他  因为他说对了
And that's why you killed him, because he was right,
他发现了你不可告人的试验
and he'd found you right in the middle of an experiment!
弗兰克兰
Frankland!
弗兰克兰  接着跑
Frankland! Keep running.
快点  跟上
Come on, keep up!
没用的  弗兰克兰
It's no use, Frankland.
谢谢  比尔
Thanks, Bill.
- 这么说他们没杀死那条狗  - 显然
- So they didn't have it put down then, the dog? - Obviously.
估计他们只是下不了手
I suppose they just couldn't bring themselves to do it.
懂了
I see.
不  你不懂
No, you don't.
- 好吧  我不懂  这算多愁善感吗  - 是的
- No, I don't. Sentiment? - Sentiment.
那个  我在实验室里是怎么回事
Listen, what happened to me in the lab?
你要加点沙司吗
Do you want some sauce with that?
我没去过山谷
I hadn't been to the Hollow.
我怎么会听到那种声音
How come I heard those things there?
你说的恐惧和刺激
Fear and stimulus, you said?
你肯定在别处被下药了  也许在实验室里
You must have been dosed with it elsewhere. In the lab, maybe?
你看到那些管子了  年代久远  可能泄露了
You saw those pipes, pretty ancient, leaky as a sieve.
而那里面是有气体的
And they were carrying the gas,
- 那  来点番茄酱吗  - 慢着
- so... Ketchup was it, or brown? - Hang on.
你以为是在糖里
You thought it was in the sugar.
你当时确定是在糖里
You were convinced it was in the sugar.
我最好快走了  火车还有一个半小时就开了
I'd better get going, there's a train leaving in half an hour,
所以如果你想...
so if you want...
老天  是你
God! It was you.
你把我关在那该死的实验室里
You locked me in that bloody lab.
- 我不得不这么做  那是个试验  - 试验
- I had to, it was an experiment. - An experiment?!
我吓坏了  夏洛克  快吓死了
I was terrified, Sherlock, I was scared to death!
我以为毒药在糖里  所以在你咖啡里放了糖
I thought the drug was in the sugar, so I put some in your coffee.
接着我找巴里莫尔少校安排了一切
Then I arranged everything with Major Barrymore.
完全科学的实验控制环境  真心的
Totally scientific, laboratory conditions, literally.
好吧  接着说  我这就来找你
All right, keep talking, I'll find you.
接着说
Keep talking.
不行  它会听到我
I can't, it'll hear me.
说你看到什么了
Tell me what you're seeing.
我不知道  但我能听见它的声音
I don't know, but I can hear it now.
我知道毒药对天才大脑的作用
I knew what effect it had had on a superior mind,
所以我得在常人的大脑上试试
so I needed to try it on an average one.
你知道我是什么意思
You know what I mean.
但药不在糖里
But it wasn't in the sugar.
我不知道你已经接触过气体了
No, well, i wasn't to know you'd already been exposed to the gas.
- 所以你搞错了  - 没有
- So you got it wrong. - No.
- 你就是错了  不在糖里  你弄错了  - 错了一点
- You were wrong. It wasn't in the sugar, you got it wrong. - A bit.
不会再错了
It won't happen again.
有长期副作用吗
Any long- term effects?
不会  你排泄掉了就没事了  我们都会这样
None at all. You'll be fine once you've excreted it. We all will.
那我想我已经搞定这个问题了
I think I might have taken care of that already.
- 你去哪  - 马上回来
- Where are you going? - I won't be a minute.
去找个男人聊聊一条狗
Got to see a man about a dog.
好吧  放他走
All right, let him go.
新福尔摩斯 第2季 第2集
Sherlock S02E02 720p hdtv x264
YYeTs人人影视
夏洛克